So, for this next other part that I want to cover with ViewRouter,
which is a very common scenario,
is we want to talk about programmatic navigation,
because it's one thing to just click a link,
but programmatically speaking,
we need to be able to say,
hey, when a user does this thing,
check these things and then send them off to a specific page.
Very common. So, I want to make sure we actually covered
that as well as dynamic route with params.
So, if you take a look back inside of our playground,
and then let's go ahead and run that now.
Great. This is good.
Okay. Home to hide that.
Playground's good.
Hide this so we don't get confused. Great.
Okay. So, at this point,
what if we wanted to do something like,
when local count is greater than 200,
it will go ahead and migrate them to Pokedex.
That's like a basic chain that we could do.
So, how might that work?
Well, if we look at our basic counter app,
base, counter, there you go.
Here we go. Inside of here.
Oh, this one's not using script setup just yet.
Do we have one that we're using script setup?
Okay. That's totally fine. Here's what we'll do.
We will basically then do it inside of here,
just so that it's easier for people to read.
Okay. So, inside of here,
we're going to import that count,
that local count from our composable that we did earlier.
Let me go ahead and grab this useCount,
and we're going to drop it over here for our app,
and then we say countStore equals useCount,
and then we can say do,
do, do, we can render out underneath here,
the H2 that says countStore.localCount.
So, what did it not like this time?
Do, do, do. Does it look composable?
All right. Hold up.
Let me just make sure we'll switch all this to
the alias to make our lives easier.
There we go. 50. See?
File names, no longer routes.
You don't have to worry about it anymore with that symbol.
Great. Okay. So, what we want to do,
if we want to be able to say when the count goes to 50,
or we increment it, right?
Let's go ahead and actually check,
and if we want, we're going to go ahead and navigate the user.
So, what we're going to do is we're going to
import the watchHelper method from view,
and so we're going to watch what?
We're going to watch countStore.localCount.
Then, what we get from this is a function
where we get the value of it,
and I believe I can just do it like this.
So, now, to show that this works,
we're going to go ahead and we're going to go ahead and
increment it. Oh, I need to increment
count because this is a local one.
So, actually, let's do globalCount just to make
our lives a little bit easier here.
So, globalCount.
There you go, there's your 200.
We can increment globalCount here,
it goes to 1200, and then there you go, 1200 up top.
You'll notice that our value is being printed out at the bottom,
as we would expect. So, that's nice.
So, it's being watched.
So, what we want to say is that, well,
if value is greater than 1200,
what do we want to do?
We want to navigate user to Pokedex.
That's the pseudo code. How do we do that?
Well, because we're inside of Composition API,
and to be honest, I think this tends to be
the easier way going forward to use with
view libraries and this is why we're going to do it this way.
We're going to go ahead and import something from View Router.
So, if you're in the options API for those from View2,
you might remember something like this.router.push.
That should look pretty familiar.
But, there's no this context inside of Composition API.
But, what we do get though is we get helper methods.
Helper methods are basically the name of
the game when it comes to View3.
So, from View Router, what do you think we called it?
Well, it is useRouter.
Because, what are we doing?
We're basically going to call the router.
So, how do we do that?
ConsRouter equals useRouter.
So, we're very explicit in what we're calling.
Then here, we can go router.push once slash Pokedex.
So, we refresh this now,
and we go ahead and go global,
global, swapped to Pokedex. That's it.
That's programmatic navigation.
Main thing being that, what do you do?
You make sure you get the router from
View Router that you can basically,
just like we did from the Composable.
It's a little helper method that says,
hey, we're going to help you do some stuff with the route.
You instantiate it here on line 10.
Then, inside of either our watch or
whatever you need to use it,
it really is just router.push.
The push semantics come from as well,
from I think the web history MDN.
So, again, we're not trying to reinvent the wheel here.
This should feel familiar.
Is a router now replaced?
Yeah, there's replace as well.
So, if you go into the View Router docs,
which again, I highly recommend
checking out when you start to dive into that stuff.
There's a ton of things that you can do
in terms of programmatic navigation.
So, we see there's push,
you can replace the location,
you can even use traversing history with the go.
Again, we're not going to play around with all this,
because this is something you can dive into as it makes sense.